we have our dispatch quiz let's look at
the solution if this instruction was
indeed issued in the previous cycle
meaning it came into the reservation
station then depending on when do we
select the instructions for execution
let's say that we do it kind of you know
towards the end of the cycle there might
not be enough time simply this
reservation station when we were
considering what can be dispatched for
execution this one simply wasn't there
yet basically in the same cycle where we
select something this got inserted here
and it wasn't inserted early enough in
the cycle so this is possibly correct it
can happen that that's basically you
cannot do both of the things
consecutively in the same cycle another
instruction was dispatched to the ad
unit this is entirely possible if for
example RS one was sent in the previous
cycle two to the execution unit then
this instruction couldn't have because
the unit can take only one instruction
so this is also possibly correct RS two
is older than Rs 3 so RS 3 cannot
dispatch until Rs 2 does this cannot be
correct because in out of order
execution and tomasulo's algorithm is
one of the out of order algorithms we
will dispatch an instruction as soon as
its operands are ready if we were
concerned about this when the operands
are ready we still don't dispatch the
instruction then we would have an
inorder processor which we don't want
actually the reason why this is an out
of order processor is because is that
instructions like this can execute even
if they are not the oldest instruction
in the reservation stations so this is
definitely not true so the correct
answers are only 1 & 2